Amelia Wang

HCI/UX Researcher

amlwng@ucsc.edu

Hello! I've led and designed academic studies for 5+ years and I'm looking for a position that uses research to bridge theory and impact. I believe in research as a tool to inspire solutions and opportunities that are user-centered and empowering.

EXPERIENCES

Robust.ai, San Carlos, CA - UX Research Intern

August 2022 - November 2022

- Worked directly under director of research and head of product to apply interviewing,
 ethnography, and observational techniques to consult clients and inform research directions
- Improved external validity of warehouse models to test on in-house
- Presented research insights/summaries and informed design directions
- Communicated product directions from user-centered point of view to help internal team understand what the product needs to do

University of California, Santa Cruz, CA - Research Assistant

Sept 2020 - Present

- Researching how digital tools can support university and community collaboration by leading studies using interviews, surveys, and qualitative analysis
- Studying relational HCl and under the advisement of Prof. David Lee, with focus on work of alignment and designing for community-engaged learning ecosystems
- Mentored 20+ undergraduates over 5 various research projects

User Empowerment Lab, UW Information School - Research Assistant

Jun 2019 - Sep 2020

- Designed, led, and ran participant studies using interviews, WoZ, and qualitative analysis to explore the social effects of voice interfaces on children advised by Alexis Hiniker in the Information School.
- Led project with one other undergrad including study design, recruitment, and qualitatively analysis.

Prosocial Computing Lab, UW Human-Centered Design & Engineering - Research Assistant

April 2017 - June 2020

- Advised by Gary Hsieh in the Human-Centered Design & Engineering Department
- Helped to design, execute, and analyze participant interviews on-site at local hospital, joint project w/ Andrea Hartzler of UW Biomedical Informatics on usability of hospital emergency chatbot design
- Designed study of eye-tracking and webpage behavior, constructed and analyzed local database

Marketing and Communications (UMAC), UW - User Experience Intern

September 2018 - June 2019

- Worked alongside developers, designers, and content strategists to consult and improve content across the university's websites
- Conducted user research to draw insights and make improvements on web campaigns

Computing Research Association, University of Iowa - Distributed Research Experience for Undergrads (DREU)

June 2018 - Sept 2018

- HCI/Accessibility research advised by Kyle Rector in the Computer Science dept. at the University
 of Iowa as part of CRA's Distributed Research Experience for Undergrads (DREU)
- Qualitatively coded videos, transcribed and analysed interviews on inclusive design for blind users in Virtual Reality, published with 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems.

EDUCATION

University of California Santa Cruz, Santa Cruz - PhD in Computational Media Sept 2020 - June 2024

- Advised by Prof. David Lee in the Tech4Good Lab, formally joint advised with Leila Takayama **University of Washington, Seattle** *BS in Human-Centered Design & Engineering* June 2016 June 2020
- President of Society of Women Engineers, UW's largest student-run organization consisting of 20+ officers and 300+ members to promote diversity and inclusion in engineering with focus on professional development and K-12 outreach through both independent and collaborative events with other engineering groups, local organizations, and industry.

TEACHING ASSISTANT EXPERIENCES

TIM 175 Business Strategy/Information Systems, UC Santa Cruz CMPM 177 Creative Strategies for Designing Interactive Media CMPM 178 Human-Centered Design Research CMPM 115 Lead by Design: Experiential Learning Collaborative

PUBLICATIONS

Ryan Wedoff, Lindsay Ball, Amelia Wang, Yi Xuan Khoo, Lauren Lieberman, and Kyle Rector. 2019. "Virtual Showdown: An Accessible Virtual Reality Game with Scaffolds for Youth with Visual Impairments." *Proceedings of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*. CHI '19.

Alexis Hiniker, Amelia Wang, Jonathan Tran, Mingrui Ray Zhang, Jenny Radesky, Kiley Sobel, and Sungsoo Ray Hong. 2021. "Can Conversational Agents Change the Way Children Talk to People?" *In Interaction Design and Children* IDC '21.

Rafal Kocielnik, Raina Langevin, James S. George, Shota Akenaga, Amelia Wang, Darwin P. Jones, Alexander Argyle, Callan Fockele, Layla Anderson, Dennis T. Hsieh, Kabir Yadav, Herbert Duber, Gary Hsieh, and Andrea L. Hartzler. 2021. "Can I Talk to You about Your Social Needs? Understanding Preference for Conversational User Interface in Health." In CUI 2021 - 3rd Conference on Conversational User Interfaces CUI '21. (Honourable Mention)

Lauren Snyder, Ayan Anandkumar Saraf, Reggie Casanova-Perez, Sarah E. Connor, Sheba George, Amelia Wang, Darwin Jones, Georgina Mendoza, John L. Gore, Mark S. Litwin, Andrea Hartzler. 2020. Visualization Co-Design with Prostate Cancer Survivors who have Limited Graph Literacy. Visual Analytics in Healthcare (VAHC) 2020.